Justin Cano

https://jstncno.dev Santa Clara, CA | jstncno@gmail.com | 650.255.0098

ABOUT

I am currently working as a **Tech Lead** on the **Experience Studio team** at **Google**.

The Experience Studio team leads the design and production of physical spaces that tell Google's story, make Google's magic more apparent, and communicate Google's ability to grow customers' businesses into the digital age and guide their brands into the future.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, RIVERSIDE

BS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING June 2014 | Riverside, CA

LINKS

https://jstncno.dev Github://jstncno LinkedIn://justincano

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Proficient in:

TypeScript • Python • HTML/CSS JavaScript

With some experience in:

Scala • Bash • C/C++ • Java • SQL

FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS

Angular • React • Unity Hadoop • Spark • Airflow

PLATFORMS

macOS • Linux • Windows Raspberry Pi • Arduino GCP • AWS

INTERESTS

Intersection of the physical and digital Software design and development Embedded devices • AR • AI Finance • Energy • Robotics User Experience • Creative coding + various other trends in tech

WORK EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE | TECHNICAL LEAD, EXPERIENCE STUDIO

Jun 2019 - Present | Mountain View, CA

- Provide technical leadership, direction, and guidance for a team of engineers
- Regularly develop and test prototypes of new exhibit concepts
- Work with a **Project Manager** and **other stakeholders** to **create and align** project schedules
- Architected solution for **real-time messaging system** using **Kubernetes** and led migration from legacy system, resulting in **99.99% uptime**
- Created **observability dashboards** to monitor the health and status of a **global fleet** of exhibit machines
- Led development of a mission-critical Electron app used as kiosk for exhibits
- Led development of **Python and TypeScript client libraries** and distribute to external exhibit developers
- Created a **custom Debian OS USB installer** with preloaded scripts used for running exhibit software
- Contributed to the design and implementation of proprietary **show control software platform** to interface with **AV systems** (e.g. Crestron)
- Collaborate with **cross-disciplinary teams** to design, develop, and deploy interactive technology exhibits

K2 PARTNERING SOLUTIONS @ GOOGLE | EXPERIENCE ENGINEER

Sep 2017 - Jun 2019 | Mountain View, CA

• Developed **software applications** for **physical spaces** that personify Google in the real world, playfully showcasing **Google technology** to inspire wonder and delight to **Google's top clients**

RALLY HEALTH | SOFTWARE DATA ENGINEER

Sep 2015 - Sep 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- Maintained on-call SRE on analytics pipeline for nightly data aggregation jobs
- Contributed to the development of client libraries for collecting analytics
- Developed software release automation and CI/CD processes using Jenkins

INSIGHT DATA SCIENCE | DATA ENGINEERING FELLOW

Jun 2015 - Jul 2015 | Palo Alto, CA

- Participated in a **Data Engineering Fellowship** to learn how to use and implement Big Data tools in the Hadoop ecosystem
- Built a data pipeline that extracts and builds a hyperlink graph from Common Crawl's April 2015 web corpus using HDFS, Spark, GraphX, and HBase

LOQATE | SUPPORT ENGINEER

Nov 2014 - May 2015 | San Mateo, CA

• Provided software support and bug fixes in C++ for clients

UCR ENTOMOLOGY | EMBEDDED SYSTEMS DEVELOPER

Jun 2014 – Jul 2014 | Riverside, CA https://jstncno.dev/dl/Kistner-et-al.pdf

• Developed **Raspberry Pi camcorder** for the University of California, Riverside Entomology Department to **aid research** of the Brown Marmorated Stink Bug

JETHEAD DEVELOPMENT | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Jun 2013 - Sep 2013 | Carlsbad, CA

• Provided C++ bug fixes and enhancements for DirecTV Set-Top-Boxes